Guide to the Frank Parsons Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Frank Parsons papers
1888-1908
MS 11
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(10 boxes)
Correspondence, notes and manuscripts for books and articles, and other documents and papers of Frank Parsons, lawyer, educator, and lecturer and writer on economics and social reform. There is very little material of a personal nature. Included is a file of correspondence with Ralph Albertson, a close friend of Parsons, mainly concerned with the cooperative movement.
Parsons, Frank, 1854-1908
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Hazel Hammond Albertson, 1946.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Separated Materials
Box 3 was decommissioned. Contents transferred to the Ralph Albertson Papers, MS 1752.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in five series: I. Documents. II. Personal Materials. III. Correspondence. IV. Writings. V. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
The Frank Parsons Papers consist of ten boxes of correspondence and writings by, to or relating to Frank Parsons, (1854-1908), political scientist, lawyer, teacher, and lecturer and writer on economics and social reform. There are two boxes of letters by or to his intimate friend and associate, Ralph Albertson, and a few papers involving the latter's settlement of Parsons' estate; also, one folder of letters to Dr. Charles Fremont Taylor, editor and publisher.
After graduating from Cornell University in 1873, Parsons worked for a railroad, taught school and was admitted to the Boston Bar. He worked as chief clerk of a law firm for a time and then opened his own office. Mr. Parsons also worked for Little and Co., publishers, as a text book writer, gave public lectures on economics and sociology and taught in college. As recorded in WHO WAS WHO IN AMERICA, his positions and distinctions include: professor of history and political science, Kansas Agricultural College, 1897-1900; professor of political science and dean of the College of Liberal Arts, Ruskin University; director of the history department, Bureau of Economic Research, Washington during which time he testified before the U.S. Industrial Commission on public ownership of railroads, telegraphs and telephones, 1901-1902; traveled throughout Europe and America studying railway systems, co-operative institutions, etc.; lectured in leading cities of Pacific Slope for the University Extension Association of Chicago. Mr. Parsons was the author of the Following books: The Story of New Zealand, 1904; The Heart of the Railroad Problem, 1906; and, The Railways, The Trusts and the People, 1906. He was born in Mount Holly, New Jersey and died there unmarried in 1908.
The Parsons correspondence contains very little of a personal nature, but concerns projects in which he was interested, such as Boston University Breadwinne's College, Kansas State Agricultural College, Ruskin College of Social Science, municipal government, municipal ownership of public utilities, the eight-hour day (one folder from educators, public officials, etc.) settlement, work, vocational guidance, etc. Among many persons represented in this correspondence, with number of letters as indicated, are Susan B. Anthony (2), Phineas T. Barnum (1), Alice Stone Blackwell (1), Edward Bellamy (2), Phillips Brooks (3), John R. Commons (2); also one to Albertson, Ernest Howard Crosby (2), Eugene V. Debbs (1), Henry George (2), Washington Gladden (2), Senator George F. Hoar (1 of 11 pages), Dr. Oliver Wendell Holmes (2), William Dean Howells (2), Marietta Holley (4), Mary Ashton (Rice) Livermore (1), Robert M. La Follette, Sr. (2), Francis Parkman (1), Jacob Riis (2).
The letters to Ralph Albertson, other than those from friends and members of his family and those concerned with Parsons' affairs, are mainly from persons interested in the cooperative movement and The American Co-operator, of which Albertson was editor, 1900-1904; and persons previously associated with him in the Christian Commonwealth, Andrews North Carolina, and Commonwealth, Georgia, experiments in which he played a major part, 1895-1900. Several from Mr. and Mrs. R.J. Kendall, 1904-1905, written from Los Mochis, Distrito del Fuerte, Sinaloa, Mexico, where there was apparently an American colony, give interesting comments on conditions there.
By far the major part of this collection is made up of addresses, lecture notes, and outlines, manuscripts of articles, etc., by Frank Parsons. The subjects include a wide variety of interests such as astronomy, civics, health, humor, industrial education, labor, legal doctrines and social progress, literature, logic, and eloquence, the cooperative movement, eight-hour day, ethics, geology, municipal ownership, marriage, and government, political economy, railways, schools, social reform suffrage, trusts and monopolies, and youth guidance. Included are a few papers by other persons.
The papers were donated to the Yale University Library by Hazel (Hammond) Albertson in 1946.
Biographical / Historical
Railroad worker, lawyer, textbook editor, professor of political science at Kansas Agricultural College and Ruskin University; employed by the Bureau of Economic Research (1901-1902); active in the cooperative movement.
The American Cooperator; Cooperation; Economics; Political science; Railroads and state; Political scientists; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922; Adams, Frederick Upham, 1859-1921; Albertson, Ralph, 1866-1951; Andrews, James De Witt, 1856-1928; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891; Beauchamp, Lou J. (Lou Jenks), 1851-1920; Bellamy, Edward, 1850-1898; Bemis, Edward Webster, 1860-1930; Bennett, Samuel C. (Samuel Crocker), 1858-1925; Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1857-1950; Brawley, John P.; Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893; Brown, Brainard C.; Commons, John R. (John Rogers), 1862-1945; Crosby, Ernest, 1856-1907; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Dillon, John F. (John Forrest), 1831-1914; Donnelly, William F.; Eldridge, Albert Gould, 1885-; Ely, Richard T. (Richard Theodore), 1854-1943; Frye, William P. (William Pierce), 1831-1911; George, Henry, 1847-; Gladden, Washington, 1836-1918; Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909; Harper, Joseph D.; Hirschler, Diana; Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904; Holley, Marietta, 1836-1926; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, Jr., 1841-1935; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920; Ingalls, Melville Ezra, 1842-1914; Johnson, Tom Loftin, 1854-1911; Jones, Samuel Milton, 1846-1904; Kidd, James W.; King, George J.; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925; Livermore, Mary A. (Mary Ashton), 1820-1905; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924; Long, John D.; MacLauvin, Donald D.; Martin, John, 1864-1956; Meriweather, Lee, 1862-1966; Moffet, Edward A.; Packard, Horace, 1855-1936; Paine, Robert Treat, 1835-1910; Palache, Eliza; Parkman, Francis, 1823-1893; Parsons, Frank, 1854-1908; Peabody, Francis Greenwood, 1847-1936; Pettigrew, Richard F. (Richard Franklin), 1848-1926; Phelan, James D. (James Duval), 1861-1930; Pingree, Hazen S., 1840-1901; Pomeroy, Eltweed, 1860-; Reed, Thomas B. (Thomas Brackett), 1839-1902; Rhees, Kate; Rich, Edgar J. (Edgar Judson), 1864-1948; Riis, Jacob A. (Jacob August), 1849-1914; Rochester, Lawrence; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Sharp, Dallas Lore, 1870-1929; Shaw, Albert D. (Albert Duane), 1841-1901; Smith, J. Burritt (Jabez Burritt); Spahr, Charles B. (Charles Barzillai), 1860-1904; Stevenson, Katharine Lent, 1853-1919; Strong, Josiah, 1847-1916; Thompson, Carl Dean, 1870-1949; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; Vrooman, Hiram, 1871-; Wanamaker, John, 1838-1922; Washburn, George Frederic, 1859-; Williams, George Fred, 1852-1932; Williams, Stephen D.; Wolfe, Richard; Wolff, Henry W. (Henry William), 1840-1931; Wright, Carroll D., 1854-1911; Zueblin, Charles, 1866-1924; National Society for Promotion of Industrial Education; People's Sovereignty League
- DOCUMENTS, 1902-1907; Series I; 0.25; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Documents are in alphabetical arrangement by name of organization. Included are memoranda, incorporation papers, constitution, bylaws and outline. Organizations found here are Codex Publishing Company, Cooperation Association of America, People's Sovereignty League, Trustees Cooperative Shoe Company, and Workers' Cooperative Association.
  - Codex Publishing Company, Memoranda of Agreement, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cooperation Association of America, Incorporation papers, 1902-1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - People's Sovereignty League, National Constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Trustees Cooperative Shoe Company, Outline of a Proposed Plan, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Workers' Cooperative Association, By-laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- PERSONAL MATERIALS, 1899, 1905-1906, 1908; Series II; 0.25; (1 box)
  Personal Materials contains biographical data, diary, materials concerning teaching at Kansas State Agricultural College and a working hours petition solicited by Frank Parsons.
  - Biographical Data, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kansas State Agricultural College, Materials pertaining to his teaching, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eight-hour Day Movement Petitions Solicited by Frank Parsons, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1888-1908; Series III; .75 linear feet (2 Boxes)
  This series is divided into two sections: the correspondence of Frank Parsons and the correspondence of Ralph Albertson. Both sections are in alphabetical sequence according to last name of senders or recipients. Miscellaneous and unidentified materials are in folders filed alphabetically under M and U.
  Parsons' correspondence includes material with Susan B. Anthony, Phineas T. Barnum, Samuel Longhorne Clemens, Eugene V. Debs, Washington Gladden, Oliver Wendell Holmes, William Dean Howells, Robert M. LaFollette, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jacob A. Riis, Theodore Roosevelt, John Wanamaker and others.
  Correspondence of Ralph Albertson contains letters with William Randolph Hearst, Robert F. Herrick, John Wanamaker and others.
  - Correspondence of Frank Parsons
    - Abbot, Lyman, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Adams, Frederick Upham, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Albertson, Ralph, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Andrews, James D., 1906-1908 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Anthony, Susan B., 1896, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Barnum, Phineas T., 1890 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Beauchamp, Lou J., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bellamy, Edward, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bemis, Edward W., 1899-1907 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bennett, Samuel C., 1898 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bethany, C.R, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bode, F.H., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Boston, Supt. of Schools, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Brawley, John P., undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Brooks, Phillips, 1888-1891 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Brown, Brainard C., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chance, W. C., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Cherry, B.F., 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Clemens, Samuel Longhorne, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Committee of One Hundred, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Commons, John R., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Crosby, Ernest Howard, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Danville (Va.) Water, Gas and Electric Light Departments, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Debs, Eugene V., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Dillon, John F., 1892 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Donnelly, Wm. F., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Eight-Hour Day Movement, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Eldridge, Albert G., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Ely, Richard T., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Fisher, R.D., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Frye, William P., 1890 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - George, Henry, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Gladden, Washington, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Hale, Edward E., 1901 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Harper, Joseph D., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Hirschler, Diana, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Hoar, George F., 1890 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Hoffman, C.B., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Holley, Marietta, 1890-1895 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1890-1906 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Howells, William Dean, 1896-1907 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Ingalls, M.E., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - International Lecture Association (Monroe, F.H.), 1907 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Introduction, Letters of, 1902, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Irish, F.L., 1898 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Johnson, Tom L., 1901 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Jones, Samuel M., 1898-1900 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Kidd, Dr. James W., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - King, George J., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - LaFollette, Robert M., 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Livermore, Mary A., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Lodge, Henry C., 1890 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Long, John D., 1890 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - MacLauvin, Donald D., 1901 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Martin, John, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Meriweather, Lee, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Miscellaneous, 1894-1908 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Moffet, Edward A., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - National Society for Promotion of Industrial Education, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - New York City, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Packard, Horace, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Paine, Robert Treat, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Palache, Eliza, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 72a)
    - Parkman, Francis, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 72b)
    - Peabody, Francis, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - People's Sovereignty League, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Pettigrew, R.F., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Phelan, James D., 1900 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Pingree, Hazen S., 1900 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Pomeroy, Eltweed, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Potter, H.P., 1900 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Recommendation, Letters of, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Reed, Thomas B., 1896 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Rhees, Miss Kate, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Rich, Edgar J., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Riis, Jacob A., 1896 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Rochester, Lawrence, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Ruskin College, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Sharp, D.L., 1900 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Shaw, Albert, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Smith, J. Burritt, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Spahr, Charles B., 1898 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Stevenson, Katherine L., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Strong, Josiah, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Taylor, C.F., 1900-1906 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Thompson, Carl D., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Toronto, Canada, Mayor of, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Unidentified, 1901, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - "Veritas", 1908 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Vrooman, Hiram, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Wanamaker, John, 1895-1898 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Warren, W.F., 1900-1902 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Washburn, George F., 1908 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Watters, W.H., 1908 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Willard, J.Y., 1899 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Williams, George Frederick, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Williams, Stephen D., 1900 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Wolfe, Richard, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Wolff, Henry W., 1904 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Wright, Carroll D, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Zueblin, Charles, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 110)
- WRITINGS, 1890, 1894-1895, 1897-1908; Series IV; 3 linear feet (6 Boxes)
  Writings contain books, parts of books, articles, addresses, lectures, outlines and notes, other people's writings and miscellaneous material which is found near the end of the series. Within each type, the material is listed alphabetically by either title, author or subject heading.
  Two books are located in this series, Legal Doctrine and Social Progress and Youth and the World. Also included is part of a book entitled Municipal Operation vs. Private Operation of Municipal Monopolies. Major subjects of articles, addresses and lectures include: strikes, public and private ownership and management of business operations, American economic history, railroads, education, the eight-hour day, and law.
  Outlines and notes contain many topics including: ancient and medieval history, humor and wit, logic, and municipal government. In Miscellaneous are letters to the editors, suggestions on Boston city government, a brief on mail, poems and fragments of writings.
  - Books
    General
    Box 3 was decommissioned. There are no folders numbered 111-240.
    - Legal Doctrine and Social Progress, typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 241)
    - Legal Doctrine and Social Progress, corrected typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 242)
    - Youth and the World, complete typescript through Chapter XVI, undated (Box 2, Folder 243)
    - Youth and the World ,complete typescript through Chapter XVI, another copy, undated (Box 4, Folder 244)
    - Youth and the World, incomplete typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 245)
    - Youth and World,, fragments, undated (Box 4, Folder 246)
  - Parts of books
    - Municipal Operation Vs. Private Operation of Municipal Monopolies, galley proofs, undated (Box 4, Folder 247)
  - Articles
    - "The Abolition of Strikes, or the Administration of Justice in Labor Disputes", undated (Box 4, Folder 248)
    - "Autobiography of a Damn Fool", undated (Box 4, Folder 249)
    - "The Bon "[illegible]", undated (Box 4, Folder 250)
    - "Chicago's Traction Battle", undated (Box 4, Folder 251)
    - "Debt and Taxation Under Municipal Ownership", undated (Box 4, Folder 252)
    - "Dewey's Ships", undated (Box 4, Folder 253)
    - "Dr. Gates and the American Book Company", 1897 (Box 4, Folder 254)
    - "Economic Babies", undated (Box 4, Folder 255)
    - "Equal Suffrage", undated (Box 4, Folder 256)
    - "A Fable for Gas Consumers", undated (Box 4, Folder 257)
    - "Glimpses of Municipal Progress", 1904 (Box 4, Folder 258)
    - "A Good Way to Pass Next Sunday Evening", undated (Box 4, Folder 259)
    - "Government by the People", undated (Box 4, Folder 260)
    - "Great Movements of the Nineteenth Century", 1901 (Box 4, Folder 261)
    - "How the Public Ownership Commission Did Its Work", 1907 (Box 4, Folder 262)
    - "The Ideal City Government", undated (Box 4, Folder 263)
    - "Incentives to Literary Effort", 1895 (Box 4, Folder 264)
    - "Insurance Without Premiums", undated (Box 4, Folder 265)
    - "Laides Stores in Boston and Paris", undated (Box 4, Folder 266)
    - "Lawless Emancipation of the Cities of Ohio", undated (Box 4, Folder 267)
    - "Lessons in Municipal Ownership", a series of newspaper articles, undated (Box 4, Folder 268)
    - "Lessons in Municipal Ownership" a series of newspaper articles, undated (Box 4, Folder 269)
    - "McKinley Prosperity and the Mckinley Dinner Pail", 1900 (Box 5, Folder 270)
    - "The National Biscuit Company's Church", undated (Box 5, Folder 271)
    - "The New Ideal", undated (Box 5, Folder 272)
    - "The New Political Economy", undated (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - "On Waking Tuesday April 5, 1898" (Box 5, Folder 274)
    - "Organization for Business Development and Civic and Social Betterment", undated (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - "Our Country: Dangers to be Averted", 1895 (Box 5, Folder 276)
    - "The Power of the Ideal", 1899 (Box 5, Folder 277)
    - "Public Ownership", undated (Box 5, Folder 278)
    - "Railways and Tramways in Foreign Countries", a series of articles, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 279)
    - "Railways in Politics", undated (Box 5, Folder 280)
    - "Railways in the United States" a series of articles, 1902-1905 (Box 5, Folder 281)
    - "Reform by Earthquake", undated (Box 5, Folder 282)
    - "The Richmond Investigation", 1906 (Box 5, Folder 283)
    - "The School City: A New System of Moral and Civic Training", undated (Box 5, Folder 284)
    - "Shall Our Mothers, Wives, and Sisters Be Our Equals or Our Subjects?", undated (Box 5, Folder 285)
    - "Shall the Public Schools be Abolished", undated (Box 5, Folder 286)
    - "The Sliding Scale and the Boston Gas Situation", undated (Box 5, Folder 287)
    - "Social Ideals", undated (Box 5, Folder 288)
    - "State and Citizenship", complete typescript, After 1900 (Box 5, Folder 289)
    - "State and Citizenship", another copy, after 1900 (Box 5, Folder 290)
    - "A Store Democracy", 1905 (Box 5, Folder 291)
    - "Suffrage Conditions", undated (Box 5, Folder 292)
    - "A System of Character Teaching for the Public Schools", undated (Box 5, Folder 293)
    - "The Telephone Question", undated (Box 5, Folder 294)
    - "Trial Marriages Already Possible Under the Laws of Massachusetts", undated (Box 5, Folder 295)
    - "Trusts and Monopolies", a series of newspaper articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 296)
    - "The Truth at the Heart of Capitalism and of Socialism", 1906 (Box 5, Folder 297)
    - "Two Views of Roosevelt", undated (Box 6, Folder 298)
    - "Wanted: A Discriminating Earthquake", undated (Box 6, Folder 299)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Addresses
    - Boston City Club Opening Address, undated (Box 6, Folder 301)
    - The City of the Future, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 302)
    - Direct Legislation, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 303)
    - The Eight-Hour Movement, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 304)
    - Freedom in Russia, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 305)
    - How to Live, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 306)
    - League of American Municipalities, undated (Box 6, Folder 307)
    - Municipal Ownership, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 308)
    - The President's Railroad Police, undated (Box 6, Folder 309)
    - Regulation of Railway Rates, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 310)
    - Social Contrasts, undated (Box 6, Folder 311)
  - Lectures
    - Outlines and schedules of lectures, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 312)
    - Breadwinner's College Lectures, 1905, undated (Box 6, Folder 313)
    - Business Psychology, course outline, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 314)
    - Civics lectures, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 315)
    - Law lectures, notes on Analysis, Contracts, and Evidence, undated (Box 6, Folder 316)
    - Law lectures, notes on Crimes, undated (Box 6, Folder 317)
    - Law lectures, notes on Leases, undated (Box 6, Folder 318)
    - Law lectures, notes on Negligence, Philosphy of Law and Problems for Classes, undated (Box 6, Folder 319)
    - Law lectures, notes on Torts (A-Malicious Prosecution), undated (Box 7, Folder 320)
    - Law lectures, notes, outlines of Torts (Mis-Wrongful Interference), undated (Box 7, Folder 321)
    - Law lecture, notes, outlines on Torts, original, incomplete, undated (Box 7, Folder 322)
    - Law lecture, A Great Argument and Its Flaw (Boston Water Power Case), undated (Box 7, Folder 323)
    - Law lectures, Miscellaneous Law Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 324)
    - Literature and Its Place in Our Lives, undated (Box 7, Folder 325)
    - Popular Government, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Outlines and Notes
    - Ancient and Medieval History, outlines of, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 327)
    - Astronomy, notes, outlines on, undated (Box 7, Folder 328)
    - Civics, notes, outlines, etc., undated (Box 7, Folder 329)
    - Department Store Cooperation, notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 330)
    - Drift of Thought, notes and rough draft, undated (Box 7, Folder 331)
    - Ethics, notes, outlines on, undated (Box 7, Folder 332)
    - Geology, notes, outlines on, undated (Box 7, Folder 333)
    - Health, notes on, undated (Box 7, Folder 334)
    - Humor and Wit, notebooks on, undated (Box 7, Folder 335)
    - Humor and Wit, notes on, undated (Box 8, Folder 336)
    - Industrial Education, notes, outlines on, 1906-1907 (Box 8, Folder 337)
    - Insurance, notes, outlines on, undated (Box 8, Folder 338)
    - Inventions and Progress, notes, outlines on, undated (Box 8, Folder 339)
    - Labor, notes, outlines on, undated (Box 8, Folder 340)
    - Life Philosophy, notes, outlines, 1897, undated (Box 8, Folder 341)
    - Logic, notebooks on, 1905, undated (Box 8, Folder 342)